<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alessandro Minoccheri</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alessandro Minoccheri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 14:13:16 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 14:13:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name&amp;rsquo;s Alessandro Minoccheri and I&amp;rsquo;m a software developer for Flowing living near Ravenna, Italy.
I typically work with backend PHP and Node.js applications and I love to contribute to open-source PHP projects.
I also love to contribute to Stack Overflow where my reputation is growing daily (actually near 25.000)!
You can contact me at my email address, alessandro.minoccheri@gmail.com or else you can find me on Twitter or GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony &#43; AWS Lambda Part1</title>
      <link>/post/symfony-aws-lambda-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 08:11:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/symfony-aws-lambda-part1/</guid>
      <description>Symfony is one of the most used frameworks in the PHP world. Nowadays talking about serverless is common, so it&amp;rsquo;s very important to know how to use Symfony with this technology. In the following article, I have described how to deploy a Symfony application to AWS Lambda using Bref. This is the first part, the second part will be posted very soon! Stay tuned!
Symfony AWS Lambda Part 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Bitbucket Private Repository in Your Projects</title>
      <link>/post/bitbucket-private-repository-in-your-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 08:58:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/bitbucket-private-repository-in-your-projects/</guid>
      <description>Many times you may like to use your personal private library in another project. For example, you may have many private projects that share a common library that can&amp;rsquo;t be open source for your business. You can use Packagist and pay to have a private repository or you can use Bitbucket with its FREE private repositories.
To include your private Bitbucket repository via Composer you need to add this lines into your composer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Authentications Systems Into Symfony</title>
      <link>/post/two-authentications-systems-into-symfony/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 15:43:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/two-authentications-systems-into-symfony/</guid>
      <description>Many times in your application you have a login system based on JWT Token. At a certain moment you need your application to be able to answer to a rest api request made by another application. So you can give the possibility to login with the JWT Token to it but it&amp;rsquo;s not safe. So you need to implement an api token authentication for your application but this means that your application has to manage both authenticators: JWT and Api Token.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony 4 Installation and new features</title>
      <link>/post/symfony-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 14:42:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/symfony-4/</guid>
      <description>Symfony 4 is the newest version of the one of the most famous PHP frameworks. It has been released on the 30th of November 2017 and it&amp;rsquo;s having a great success! One of the biggest difference with the older versions is the presence of very small dependencies installed when you init your Symfony 4 project. Symfony 4 is so tiny that Silex project has been dismissed.
How to Install Symfony 4 In order to create a new Symfony 4 application you need to have PHP 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better performances, high security, deprecated functions: here&#39;s  all the news about PHP 7.2</title>
      <link>/post/php7-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 15:09:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/php7-2/</guid>
      <description>PHP 7.2 has many features about security, implementations and deprecated functions. In addition, it introduces a performance increase (already in version 7 it was done a great work): PHP 7.2 is 20% faster than version 7.0 and 10% faster than version 7.1.
Here&amp;rsquo;s all the highlights offered by this new version.
Type hinting argument Since PHP 5 it was possibile to specify the argument type passed to a function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>